Gathering data from text files in Python means opening and reading from files.
在 Python 中收集文本文件的数据意味着要打开和读取文件
If you're using Pandas like we are here,
如果和我们一样 你正在使用 Pandas
then this also means storing the text data you just read in a Pandas data frame.
还意味着要在 Pandas DataFrame中存储刚读取的文本数据
We have 88 Roger Ebert reviews to open and read.
我们共有 88 条 Roger Ebert 影评要打开和读取
We'll need a loop to iterate through all of
要打开并读取文档
the files in this folder to open and read each.
我们需要循环迭代此文件夹中的所有文件
There are two main ways of doing this.
此处有两种方法可用
One using the OS library and the other using a library called glob.
一种是通过 OS 库完成 另一种是使用名为 glob 的库完成
We've been using os.listdir in this lesson so far.
在本节课中 我们目前使用的是 os.listdir
This is good if you're sure you want to open
它的效果很好
every file in the folder, like our case here.
如果你确定要打开文件夹中的每个文件 比如此处的案例
Every file in this folder is a Roger Ebert review text file.
文件夹中的每个文件都是 Roger Ebert 影评文件
But let's switch it up here and use glob instead.
但让我们换为 glob 代替
The glob library allows for Unix-style pathname pattern expansion,
glob 库允许 Unix 风格的路径名模式扩展
which is a fancy way of saying,
这是一种漂亮说法
using something called glob patterns to specify sets of filenames.
使用 glob 模式详细说明多个文件名
These glob patterns use something called wildcard characters.
这些 glob 模式使用通配符
Being introduced to documentation and looking through it like this can be overwhelming,
文档介绍和通篇浏览颇费时间
so I just want you to focus on this one thing here for now, glob.glob.
所以 我暂时想让你只看这个东西 glob.glob
This returns a list of path name that match pathname, i.e.
它会返回一个与 pathname 匹配的路径名称
the string parameter you pass in here,
即你输入此处的字符串参数
this is where the glob pattern goes.
这就是 glob 模式发挥作用的地方
How can we use this?
我们怎么用呢？
We want all file names that end in.txt,
我们想要的文件名称都以 .txt 结尾
which in this Ebert reviews folder, is all of them.
文件都在 Ebert 影评文件夹中
And because glob.glob returns a list,
因为 glob.glob 会返回一个列表
we can loop through that directly here.
我们可以直接对其循环
Here's that wildcard in the glob pattern.
这就是 glob 模式下的通配符
Everything in the folder, ebert_reviews,
文件夹中的所有项为 ebert_reviews
then every single file that ends in.txt.
然后是以 .txt 结尾的每个单独文件
This star means match any string of any length.
星号指匹配任何长度的字符串
Let's just print out the paths to all of these files here using glob.
让我们打印输出此处所有文件的路径
You can imagine how useful this would be if not
你想象得到这会有多实用
every file in this folder ended in.txt, for example.
假设此文件夹中的每个文件都没有以 .txt 结尾 例如
You can pass this entire path for each file into the open function in Python.
你可以把每个文件的完整路径传入 Python 的 open 函数中
While we've been opening files like this, with open,
在我们打开此类文件期间
then the path to the file, then,
使用 open 函数然后是文件路径 输入 as file
as file, or whatever file handle you used.
任何文件句柄均可
In Python 3, when opening text to read,
在 Python 3 中 打开文本读取时
you should actually always use open with an explicit encoding,
你应始终使用具有明确编码的 open 函数
which comes after this encoding parameter.
明确编码跟在 encoding 参数之后
Doing so means you get correctly decoded Unicode,
这样做是为了 Unicode 正确解码
or an error right off the bat,
否则立即出现错误
making it much easier to debug.
这样做让调试更容易
Again, we haven't been doing this earlier in the lesson because I didn't
再次 我们在本课程前面尚未这样处理
want to overload you with information about encodings,
因为我不想讲过多有关编码的知识
but now is a good time to start.
但现在正是讲讲的好时机
And going forward, all of your opening code should be like this.
接下来打开的代码应该是这样的
What's the actual encoding?
实际编码是什么？
That depends on the source of the text.
那取决于文本来源
Let's use Roger Ebert's review for the movie Casablanca as a working example.
我们使用 Roger Ebert 对电影 《卡萨布兰卡》 的影评文件作为操作范例
But keep in mind, this applies to all of
但要记住 这适用于所有此类文件
these files because they are all from the same website.
因为它们采集自同一个网站
If we inspect this page's source,
如果我们要检查本页面来源
which you can do in various browsers by right clicking
可以在其它浏览器中
and selecting View page source or something of like,
右键点击 “查看页面源代码”或类似选项
you'll find that the encoding here is utf-8.
你会发现此处的编码是 utf-8
Great. Let's open up the text file for this movie, Casablanca.
很好 让我们打开这部电影的文本文件
We actually don't want all of this text data in one big chunk though,
实际上 我们不想要所有文本数据都在一个数据块中
which would be done like this,
而应这样操作
file.read, which we can check for one of the files in
输入file.read ( ) 我们可以借助 print 语句检查 glob 循环中的一个文件
this glob loop with a print statement and then a break from the loop.
然后断开循环
There is the entirety of the Wizard of Oz file,
这是《绿野仙踪》文件的全部影评
which is the first file in the folder.
它是文件夹中的第一个文件
Instead, we want the first line, a.k.a.
相反 我们想要的是第一行 即这部电影名
the movie title, the second line, a.k.a.
想要的第二行 即 URL
the URL, and then everything from the third line onwards, a.k.a.
然后从第三行的之后的所有内容 即影评文本
the review text, as separate pieces of data,
我们想要这三项作数据独立存在
so we can't just use file.read.
所以 我们不能只使用 file.read
Since text files are separated by
由于文本文件被换行符隔开
newline characters and the file object returned from with open,
而且通过 with open as file 返回的文件对象是
as file, is an iterator,
一个迭代文件
we can read the file line by line.
我们可以逐行读取文件
If you just want to read one line,
如果你只是想读取一行
you use.readline, like so, file.readline.
你会用 .readline 像这样
Let's check this out using the print and break strategy again.
使用 print 检查 再次使用 break 策略
There is the title of the movie on the first line of the file,
文件第一行是电影名称
and it's actually a bit of white space below here,
此处下方实际上有一些空行
which is actually the \n,
这实际上是 \n
or the newline character.
或者说换行符
We can get rid of that by slicing it off at the end of these string.
我们可以在这些字符串的末尾进行切片
There we go, we've got the movie title.
就这么办 于是我们得到了电影名称
Next, you're going to grab the URL and the full review text.
接下来 你将捕获 URL 和完整的影评文本
But before that, recall that we want all this data in a Pandas data frame,
在此之前 回想下我们想要所有此类数据都在 pandas DataFrame 中
so we need to build one.
所以 我们需要创建一个DataFrame
The most computationally efficient way to do that is first to create
最具计算效率的方法是
an empty list then populate that list one by one as we iterate through this loop,
首先创建一个空表 然后在循环迭代过程中逐一填充表格
and we'll fill this list with dictionaries.
我们用字典填充此列表
That list of dictionaries will later be converted to a Pandas data frame,
然后将此列表转换成 Pandas DataFrame
all at once, once all of the data has been gathered.
一下子 所有收据都收集好了
Now, it's your turn. Your task is to grab the review URL,
现在 轮到你操作了 你的任务是获取影评 URL
and then the full review text,
然后获取完整影评文本
and then append it to the list of dictionaries.
并将其“添加 (append)” 到字典列表